<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <string name="lesson_1_title">Lesson 1. Starting Learning</string>
    <string-array name="lesson_1_text">
        <item>Mandarin Chinese is spoken by over a billion people worldwide!</item>
        <item><![CDATA[<big><b>Learning Chinese</b></big>]]></item>
        <item>Chinese is not as difficult as you think! While the sounds and characters may be intimidating at first, Chinese grammar is actually easier than many other languages.</item>
        <item><![CDATA[<big><b>What is pinyin?</b></big>]]></item>
        <item>Chinese doesn\'t have an alphabet like English. Instead of using letters to represent sounds, Chinese characters (like 好, which means good) represent entire words. A word can also have more than one character (for example 高兴, which means happy).</item>
        <item>To make things easier, pinyin represents the sounds of Mandarin Chinese using the Roman alphabet. The common greeting 你好 (hello) is written below using letters you will recognize.</item>
        <item><![CDATA[<big><b>Tones</b></big>]]></item>
        <item>A big difference between Chinese and English is the use of tones. In Chinese, the inflection you use to pronounce a syllable can create a new word entirely.</item>
        <item>In English, you might be shouting (Mom!), asking a question (Mom?), or complaining (Mah‑ummm!), but the meaning of Mom never changes.</item>
        <item>This is not the case for Chinese! The basic sounds that make up the word for mother can easily mean horse… if you pronounce them with a different tone!</item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="lesson_1_words">
        <item>妈</item>
        <item>麻</item>
        <item>马</item>
        <item>骂</item>
    </string-array>
    <string name="lesson_2_title">Lesson 2. Numbers</string>
    <string-array name="lesson_2_text">
        <item>Counting in Chinese is as easy as 一 , 二 , 三 ! Next time you walk up a flight of stairs, practice a Chinese number with each step!</item>
        <item><![CDATA[0 ‑ 零 (líng)<br />1 ‑ 一 (yī)<br />2 ‑ 二 (èr)<br />3 ‑ 三 (sān)<br />4 ‑ 四 (sì)<br />5 ‑ 五 (wǔ)<br />6 ‑ 六 (liù)<br />7 ‑ 七 (qī)<br />8 ‑ 八 (bā)<br />9 ‑ 九 (jiǔ)<br />10 ‑ 十 (shí)<br />100 ‑ 百 (bǎi)]]></item>
        <item>Numbers 11‑100 are formed by combining the numbers above.</item>
        <item><![CDATA[18 ‑ 十八 (shíbā)<br />30 ‑ 三十 (sānshí) <br />56 ‑ 五十六 (wǔshíliù)<br />100 ‑ 一百 (yìbǎi)]]></item>
        <item><![CDATA[<big><b>Money</b></big>]]></item>
        <item>Yuan is the main unit of currency in China. To say how much something costs, just add 元 (yuán) after the number. You may also see the yuan sign ¥.</item>
        <item><![CDATA[¥8 ‑ 八元 (bā yuán)<br />¥40 ‑ 四十元 (sìshí yuán)<br />¥83 ‑ 八十三元 (bāshísān yuán)]]></item>
        <item><![CDATA[<big><b>Tones</b></big>]]></item>
        <item>Remember that Chinese has four tones, often referred to as the first, second, third, and fourth tone.</item>
    </string-array>
    <string name="lesson_3_title">Lesson 3. Name</string>
    <string-array name="lesson_3_text">
        <item><![CDATA[<big><b>Chinese Syllables</b></big>]]></item>
        <item>Chinese syllables usually contain three parts: an initial (like g, k, or h), a final that contains at least one vowel (for example, a, ao, or ing), and a tone marking.</item>
        <item><![CDATA[<big><b>Initial Sounds</b></big>]]></item>
        <item>Pinyin letters b, p, m, f are pronounced similarly to sounds in English.</item>
        <item><![CDATA[<big><b>Chinese Names</b></big>]]></item>
        <item>In Chinese, the family name comes first, followed by the given name (or what we might call first name in English). In the example below, 李 (Lǐ) is the family name and 华 (Huá) is the given name.</item>
        <item>It is common in China for people to call each other by their family names. To ask someone\'s family name, you can use 姓 (xìng).</item>
        <item><![CDATA[<big><b>Asking Questions with 呢 (ne)</b></big>]]></item>
        <item>呢 (ne) is used at the end of a sentence to ask things like And you? or What about her? It normally answers a question that’s just been asked while directing the question to someone else.</item>
    </string-array>
    <string name="lesson_4_title">Lesson 4. Greeting</string>
    <string-array name="lesson_4_text">
        <item><![CDATA[<big><b>Initial Sounds</b></big>]]></item>
        <item>Pinyin letters d, t, n, and l represent four more sounds pronounced similarly to sounds in English.</item>
        <item><![CDATA[<big><b>Tones</b></big>]]></item>
        <item>The trick to remembering the 2nd and 4th tone is to think of them as rising (2nd) and falling (4th).</item>
        <item><![CDATA[<big><b>Very Good! 很好 (hěn hǎo)</b></big>]]></item>
        <item>In English, we say I am good or She is happy, but in Chinese you don’t use words like am or is before adjectives. Instead, adjectives are usually preceded by 很 (hěn). Sometimes 很 means very, but it’s more often just a way to connect a noun and an adjective.</item>
        <item><![CDATA[<big><b>也 (yě, also)</b></big>]]></item>
        <item>In English, we can say I am happy, too or I’m also happy, but in Chinese the word for also or too (也) always comes before the adjective.</item>
    </string-array>
    <string name="lesson_5_title">Lesson 5. Food</string>
    <string-array name="lesson_5_text">
        <item><![CDATA[<big><b>Initial Sounds</b></big>]]></item>
        <item>Pinyin letters g, k, h, and s are pronounced similarly to sounds in English.</item>
        <item><![CDATA[<big><b>也 (yě, also)</b></big>]]></item>
        <item>You already know that 也 (yě), which means also or too, always comes before the adjective (for example, 我也很高兴, wǒ yě hěn gāoxìng). The same applies when 也 is used with verbs.</item>
        <item><![CDATA[<big><b>不 (bù, not)</b></big>]]></item>
        <item>In English, we say I do not eat noodles or He does not eat noodles. To negate a sentence in Chinese, you only need to add no (不 bù) before the verb. Easy peasy!</item>
    </string-array>
</resources>